If you collect 99 devil's keys…
只要集齐99把钥匙…
Jump!
快跳
…you can have everything in the world.
…就能在世界上呼风唤雨
The mysterious organization Gungnir is holding an ACMA:GAME tournament.
神秘组织永恒之枪举办了一个 ACMA:GAME恶魔游戏锦标赛
If it'll help my family, I'll manage.
为了家人 我会坚强起来的
I beat Yukari, and even though Yuki lost to Senya, I managed to save her family.
我打败了紫 虽然悠季输给了潜夜 但我成功救出了她的家人
What is Gungnir's plan behind all this?
永恒之枪到底要做什么？
The creation of a new world map
他们的目的是创造新的世界地图
under the leadership of Our Great Guide.
一切都由伟大的引领者领导
If you want to know more, you'll have to beat me.
你想知道的话 得先战胜我
My dear friends who made it through the first round,
在第一轮中胜出的各位选手
let me first say congratulations.
首先恭喜你们
We're adding a new twist in the second round with team games.
第二轮会改变一下 进行团体赛
Your teammate is whoever you played against in the first round.
你们将会和第一轮的对手组成一队
In the first game, Teruasa Oda and Yukari Shikibe
在第一场比赛中 织田照朝和式部紫
will battle against Ui Saito and Shunichiro Date.
将对战齐藤初和伊达俊一郎
In the second game, Senya Uesugi and Yuki Manabe
在第二场比赛中 上杉潜夜和真锅悠季
will battle against Akira Mori and Mitsuru Asai.
将对战毛利明和浅井满
First,
首先
tell us what you mean by "creating a new world."
“创造新世界”是什么意思？
What are you conspiring to do with 50 keys?
你们收集了50把钥匙 有什么企图？
Shouldn't you forget that and worry about the next game instead?
与其关心这个 不如担心你的下一场比赛吧
Haven't you and Saito been best friends since middle school?
你和齐藤初 从中学起就是好朋友了吧？
Seems as though this fight was written in the stars.
真是一场命中注定的战斗啊
The first game will begin in one hour.
第一场比赛将会在一小时后进行
Mori, let's do this!
毛利君 我们加油
Great! This is gonna be fun.
好啊 这一定很有意思
Are you okay, Teruasa?
照朝君 你没事吧？
I didn't think you'd have to fight Ui.
没想到你要和初君对决
-OROCHI and I will search the hotel. -What?
-我和大蛇会搜查酒店的 -什么？
There must be devil keys somewhere.
这里一定藏有恶魔钥匙吧？
-If I can steal them－ -You mustn't.
-我去偷… -不行
Don't do anything dangerous.
不要做危险的事
-But I－ -Yuki.
-可是我… -悠季
Thank you.
谢谢
But I said I'm fine.
但是我没问题的
It's an honor to be on your team.
很荣幸能跟你一组
I'll follow your lead.
有什么要求敬请吩咐
I've been curious.
我很好奇
You went easy on me last time, didn't you?
你和我对战的时候保留实力了吧？
No.
没有
You've got it wrong.
没这种事
By the way, when you face your friend…
说起来 你和好朋友织田照朝对决时
will you go easy on him?
真的能全力以赴吗？
Never.
当然
I'll take him down with all I've got.
我会全力打败他
TOURNAMENT ROUND 2 1ST GAME
（锦标赛第2轮 第1场）
Tell me…
我说…
TERUASA ODA &amp; YUKARI SHIKIBE VS UI SAITO &amp; SHUNICHIRO DATE
（织田照朝 式部紫 对 齐藤初 伊达俊一郎）
…who is this Guide?
那个引领者是谁？
The guy at the top?
他是头目吗？
You should show respect when you speak his name.
请不要随便提引领者大人的名字
Ui,
初
what has Gungnir done to you?
永恒之枪对你做了什么？
Why would you join them?
你为什么要加入他们？
You should concentrate.
你还是专心比赛吧
Teruasa…
照朝
I'm going to defeat you.
我会打败你
Ui…
初
I summon the devil.
召唤恶魔
Did you enter Ui into the tournament because he's Teruasa's friend?
（第7集）
That's not the only reason.
不仅仅是因为这个
Though his life is in turmoil because of his kind nature,
虽然他确实是因为太善良 才被卷了进来
as expected from someone chosen by the devil, he's an outstanding player.
但他被恶魔选中 是因为他很优秀
Most importantly, Saito knows Oda inside out.
最重要的是 齐藤对织田了如指掌
He will be a formidable match.
对织田来说 他将是无与伦比的劲敌
The last time I saw a team match was in Babylonia,
上次我看到团体赛 还是在巴比伦王国呢
or was it ancient Rome?
不对 是在古罗马
This game will be fitting for a two-player team game.
这次的游戏适合进行二对二的对决
"Basket Fruits."
篮子水果
"Basket Fruits"?
篮子水果？
Let me explain how the game works.
我来解释游戏规则
First, you each roll the dice,
首先每个玩家掷骰子
and sit in order around the table, from highest to lowest.
根据点数的大小决定座次
UI - YUKARI TERUASA - DATE
（初 紫 照朝 伊达）
FIG - ZUCCHINI - ORANGE PEAR - APPLE
（无花果 西葫芦 橙子 梨 苹果）
Next, you choose which fruits to put in the basket
然后你们从抽屉中选五张牌
by selecting five tiles from the drawer.
以决定要将什么水果放进篮子里
However, you can only choose up to three of the same fruit.
但是 每种水果最多只能选三张牌
FIG - ORANGE - APPLE
（无花果 橙子 苹果）
The five fruits you have chosen will appear in the center
你们选择的五种水果 将会在桌子中央的篮子中
as plain marbles that all look the same.
以外观相同的大理石珠显示
Since there are four of you, there will be 20 marbles in total.
篮子里总共有四个人的20颗石珠
You know what your own five marbles are,
除了自己的五颗石珠以外 你们不知道
but the other 15 are a mystery.
其余15颗代表什么水果
You take turns to play.
每个玩家轮流出招
When it's your turn, you choose a fruit,
轮到你们时 选择一种水果
and make a call, declaring that there is x amount or more of that fruit.
然后叫牌 猜测篮子里有多少个以上的某种水果
For example, you might say, "There are five or more figs."
例如你们可以说 “篮子里有五个或更多无花果”
FIVE OR MORE FIGS - CALL
（叫牌 有五个或更多无花果）
If the next player thinks the call is wrong, he must say, "Doubt."
如果下一位玩家认为这个猜测是错的 他可以提出质疑
DOUBT
（质疑）
If he thinks the call is right, he also chooses a fruit,
如果他觉得这个猜测是对的 那么他可以选另一种水果
and makes a new call.
然后重新叫牌
If you choose a fruit that has already been called,
如果你们要选择被叫过的水果
naturally, you must offer a greater number.
那么重新叫牌的数量要比前者多
Basically, you have to guess how many of which fruit are in the basket.
也就是说 要猜出篮子中 某种水果的数量是多少
What happens when you say "Doubt"?
提出质疑后会怎么样
I will reveal how many of that fruit there are in the basket.
我会揭晓那种水果在篮子中有多少个
In this case, there are four figs.
比如现在有四个无花果
Because the first player guessed that there were five or more,
由于第一位玩家猜测 有五个或更多无花果
the doubter is correct.
所以质疑者猜测正确
Whoever is correct wins however many points the chosen fruit is worth.
猜测正确的玩家 可以赢得所选水果的对应分数
What if the doubter is wrong?
如果质疑者猜测错误呢？
If the person who made the call is correct,
那么叫牌的玩家猜测正确
he wins however many points the chosen fruit is worth.
他将赢得所选水果对应的分数
A fig is worth one point, a zucchini is two points,
无花果是一分 西葫芦是两分
an orange is three points, a pear is four points,
橙子是三分 梨是四分
and an apple is five points.
苹果是五分
The numbers are in the words.
这里用到了日语的谐音
F1g, 2ucchini,
无花果音似“一” 西葫芦音似“二”
orang3, pe4r, and a5ple.
橙子音似“三” 梨音似“四” 苹果音似“五”
That's kinda lame.
好尬啊
An incorrect doubter must fold.
如果质疑者猜测错误
TERUASA - YUKARI - UI - DATE
（照朝 紫 初 伊达）
They lose the same number of points, and their tiles are revealed.
他将会被扣除相应分数 并且要亮出自己的牌
If someone declares that there are 12 or more of one fruit,
但是 如果有玩家猜测 篮子里有12个或以上的某种水果
the next player must always say "Doubt."
下一名玩家必须自动提出质疑
Twelve fruits…
12个水果…
I don't see how everyone would choose three of the same fruit.
每个人不可能 同时选三张相同的水果牌
How do you win?
怎么算赢？
Once three people are out, the set is over.
当三个人全出局 只剩最后一人时 每局结束
At the end of each set, if someone has ten points, that person wins.
在每局结束时 如果有人能得到十分 他就是胜者
If there is no winner, the points are carried over,
如果没有胜者 分数会累积
and the set is repeated until someone wins.
游戏将继续 直至出现胜者
And with that, let Basket Fruits begin!
现在“篮子水果”比赛开始
You may all choose five fruits.
你们可以选择五种水果
The main gist of the game
这个游戏的关键是
is to use the fruits you choose as a clue to guess what's in the basket,
以自己选择的水果为线索 推测篮子中有什么水果
and then decide whether to doubt the caller.
然后决定要质疑还是叫牌
It must be easier to guess if I don't play too many different fruits.
自己选择的水果种类越少 就越容易推测
I can choose a maximum of three of the same fruit,
我最多可以选择三张相同的水果牌
so I'll play a set of three, and a set of two.
那我就选三张和两张相同的组合
BASKET FRUITS SET 1
（篮子水果 第一局）
Yukari Shikibe, your turn to call.
式部紫 请叫牌
There is one or more fig.
篮子里有一个或更多无花果
Shunichiro Date, do you wish to call or doubt?
伊达俊一郎 你要叫牌还是质疑？
It's only one fig, so even if I doubt her, she'll only lose one point.
只是无花果而已 如果我质疑她 那么她只会被扣一分
She took the safe option.
她打的是安全牌
There are two or more figs.
篮子里有两个或更多无花果
Teruasa Oda, do you wish to call or doubt?
织田照朝 你要叫牌还是质疑？
It makes sense to add one more fig to the previous call.
在之前叫牌的基础上再加一个数 是正确的玩法
But I don't have fig.
但是我没有无花果
If I change the fruit now, I'm basically admitting I didn't choose any figs.
如果我现在换水果 就等于承认我没选无花果
So…
所以…
There are four or more figs.
篮子里有四个或更多无花果
Ui Saito, do you wish to call or doubt?
齐藤初 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Now if he thinks I have two or more figs,
如果他以为我有两个或更多无花果
I can mislead him.
那我就成功误导他了
You can do better, Teruasa.
你真保守啊 照朝
There are seven or more apples.
篮子里有七个或更多苹果
He just up and changed the fruit?
他干脆换了一种水果？
And he started with seven?
而且一上来就是七个？
Yukari Shikibe, do you wish to call or doubt?
式部紫 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Seven out of 20 are apples?
在20张牌里有七张是苹果？
Surely I should doubt that.
我应该质疑吗？
But I played two apples.
但是我自己有两个苹果
If he's so confident it's seven, he must have played three apples.
他那么自信地说出七个苹果 证明他一定有三个苹果
With my two, that's already five apples.
再加上我的两个 就有五个了
If Date or Teruasa have two between them, that makes seven.
如果伊达或照朝有两个 那加起来就是七个
Wait, surely Teruasa…
不 照朝他一定是…
There are eight or more apples.
篮子里有八个或更多苹果
That's a good call.
叫得好
I've got three apples, so it could be enough to reach eight.
我有三个苹果 所以篮子里完全可能有八个苹果
Shunichiro Date, do you wish to call or doubt?
伊达俊一郎 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Doubt.
质疑
Then let's see.
现在开始判定
The number of apples in the basket is…
篮子里的苹果数量是…
six.
六个
Shunichiro Date, who doubted correctly, gets five points.
伊达俊一郎质疑正确 获得五分
The incorrect guesser, Yukari Shikibe, loses five points.
式部紫猜测错误 扣五分
YUKARI -5 - DATE 5
（式部紫 -5 伊达 5）
Yukari Shikibe, you're out. Now the others can see your tiles.
式部紫 你出局了 现在公开你的牌
Since you're out, move to a seat in the back.
出局者请坐到后面的位置上
There are six apples in total.
一共有六个苹果
Three of them are mine, and two of them are Yukari's.
其中两个是紫的 三个是我的
So between Ui and Date, they only have one apple.
那么初和伊达只有一个苹果
And yet, he called seven apples.
但他为什么一开始就叫七个苹果？
Teruasa,
照朝
I'm the one who knows you the best.
我对你了如指掌
Is that really all you've got?
你的全部实力真只有这些？
Gungnir is much more powerful than you.
永恒之枪比你要强大得多
Shunichiro Date, since you were correct, it's your turn to call.
伊达俊一郎刚才质疑正确 请叫牌
There are two or more zucchini.
篮子里有两个或更多西葫芦
Teruasa Oda, do you wish to call or doubt?
织田照朝 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Now that Yukari's fruits are exposed,
紫的牌已经公开了
they can guess what most of mine are.
他们可以推测我有什么牌
I mustn't make a reckless call.
我不能轻率地叫牌
Maybe this will work.
这样的话…
There are three or more oranges.
篮子里有三个或更多橙子
Ui Saito, do you wish to call or doubt?
齐藤初 你要叫牌还是质疑？
There is one or more pear.
篮子里有一个或更多梨
But there are already two pears in the basket.
已经有两个了 还叫一个？
Why would he do that?
他是什么意思？
Shit. Is that what he's doing?
糟了 难道初的目标是…
Shunichiro Date, do you wish to call or doubt?
伊达俊一郎 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Doubt.
质疑
Let's see.
现在开始判定
The number of pears in the basket is…
篮子里的梨数量是…
six.
六个
Ui Saito, who guessed correctly, wins four points.
齐藤初 你猜测正确 得四分
Shunichiro Date, who was incorrect, loses four points.
伊达俊一郎质疑错误 扣四分
Your tiles are revealed, and you're out.
现在公开你的牌 你被淘汰出局
DATE
（伊达）
Date doubted him on purpose to win points for Ui.
伊达故意质疑初 把分让给他
That was their team strategy.
这是他们的作战策略
Ui Saito, as the correct guesser, it's your turn to call.
齐藤初 刚才你猜测正确 现在请叫牌
Looks like it's a duel to the finish.
照朝 现在是单挑了
But it's already checkmate.
但是你已经无牌可打
Judging from the exposed tiles…
根据公开的牌…
TERUASA - YUKARI - UI - DATE
（照朝 紫 初 伊达）
…and from the number of apples and pears,
…以及已知的苹果和梨的数量
you must have
你一定有
three apples.
三个苹果
And two pears.
和两个梨
Let me tell you what else.
我再告诉你别的吧
"Four or more figs" has been called, but only one has been revealed.
“四个或更多无花果”已被叫过 但被公开的无花果只有一个
Even if I have three figs, it's still only four in total.
即便我有三个无花果 那么加起来也只有四个
So I can't call, "five or more figs."
所以我不能叫“五个或更多无花果”
"Two or more zucchini," was also called, but since neither of us has one,
“两个或更多西葫芦”也被叫过了 但由于我们都没有西葫芦
only the two on display are confirmed.
所以西葫芦全在公开的牌里了
DATE
（伊达）
I can't raise the call higher for zucchini either.
我也不能增加西葫芦的数量
So the only option left is oranges.
所以剩下的选项只有橙子
Only one is out in the open.
公开的牌里只有一个橙子
DATE
（橙子）
Since you don't have one,
而你没有橙子
this is the only call worth making.
所以橙子最高只能叫这个数
There are four or more oranges.
篮子里有四个或更多橙子
You can't raise the guess any higher.
你没法叫比这个更高的数
Your only option left is to doubt me.
你唯一的选择就是质疑我
Ui must have three oranges.
初一定有三个橙子
So there are four in the basket.
所以篮子里总共有四个
If I doubt him, I'll lose.
如果我质疑他 那我就输了
Teruasa Oda, do you wish to call or doubt?
织田照朝 你要叫牌还是质疑？
If he's lying about not having any zucchini, maybe I should call.
如果他说没有西葫芦是假的 那我是不是该叫牌？
No,
不
he's not the type to tell a cheap lie.
那家伙不是会撒谎的人
But then…
这样的话…
the only option is "doubt," even though I know I'm wrong.
我明知道会失败也只能提出质疑吗？
Teruasa Oda, do you wish to call or doubt?
织田照朝 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Wait.
不对
The best option in this situation is…
在这种情况下 最好的选择是…
There are 12 or more…
篮子里有12个或更多…
figs.
无花果
Since Teruasa called 12 fruit, Ui Saito must doubt his guess by default.
由于照朝叫了12个无花果 所以齐藤初自动提出质疑
The number of figs in the basket is…
篮子里无花果的数量是…
two.
两个
Ui Saito wins one point.
齐藤初质疑正确 得一分
Teruasa Oda loses one point
织田照朝猜测错误 扣一分
and is out of the set.
并被淘汰出局
TERUASA -1 UI 5
（照朝 -1 初 5）
Now that three players are out,
由于已经有三位玩家出局
the first set is finished.
因此第一局结束
You scraped through with minus one because you were careful not to doubt me.
你刻意不提出质疑 以负一分的结果逃过一劫
That was a good decision.
这确实是个正确的选择
I've been totally defeated in this set.
我在这一局完全败下阵来
Now, Teruasa,
我说 照朝
you better come at me with everything you've got.
你最好给我拿出浑身解数
Ui, what's making you do this?
初 你为何这么做？
There doesn't seem to be anything unusual.
这里似乎没有任何异常
They must be keeping 50 keys somewhere safe.
他们一定将50把钥匙 藏在了某个地方吧？
Maybe they're not in the hotel after all?
莫非这些钥匙根本不在酒店里？
Your approach was right.
你的战术没有问题
Ui just got ahead of us somehow.
初只是刚好表现得比我们好而已
I'll do anything to make sure you win.
我会尽我所能让你赢的
Yukari－
紫…
So tell me everything about Ui Saito.
所以跟我说说齐藤初吧
Whoa, how'd you get so good?
初 你怎么这么厉害了？
You could barely hit the ball the other day.
之前你连球都很难打中
I just practiced.
我只是多加练习了而已
I want to be as good as you.
我想像你一样厉害
But even with practice, you got good at lightning speed.
就算有练习 你的进步也太快了
Whatever situation he finds himself in, Ui never gives up.
初在任何情况下都不轻言放弃
Whatever he does, he does it with full conviction.
那家伙做起事来 总是怀着坚定的信念
He's not the kind of guy to be driven by greed.
他不是那种被欲望驱使的人
That's why I want to believe he must have a reason for joining Gungnir.
因此我相信 他加入永恒之枪一定另有原因
Yukari, we need a strategy for the second set.
紫 我们需要制定第二局的作战策略
Yes.
嗯
I've been thinking.
我在想
The apple is worth the most points,
苹果的分数最高
so it does the most damage if you're wrong.
所以在猜错时 被扣的分也最多
Let's use that to get the upper hand.
那我们就利用这一点
Ui will call the lowest number of apples possible.
初在指定苹果时 应该会尽可能从最低的数量开始叫牌
Then Date will repeat his strategy, trying to fail on purpose
然后伊达会重复他的策略 故意输掉比赛
so he can win points for Ui.
让初赢得分数
Yes, we need to block their strategy.
我们首先要牵制他们
BASKET FRUITS SET 2
（篮子水果 第二局）
Teruasa Oda, make the first call.
织田照朝 请叫牌
There are three or more apples.
篮子里有三个或更多苹果
Ui Saito, do you wish to call or doubt?
齐藤初 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Three apples.
三个苹果
That's a bold start.
真是个大胆的开始
I guess you think I'm going to get Date to win points for me again?
这一次你们以为 我会让伊达再次把分让给我？
If I call four or more apples,
如果我叫牌 说篮子里有四个或更多苹果
it'll be a risky move for Date to doubt me.
那么伊达质疑我就很危险
But this time,
但是这一次
I had Date choose three apples.
我让伊达选了三个苹果
Teruasa,
照朝
I know you too well. If you call three apples,
我太了解你了 如果你叫牌说有三个苹果
you probably have one in your hand.
那么你的手上大概率有一个苹果
Crap, how did he figure that out?
糟糕 他是怎么知道的？
So with Date's three apples,
也就是说 加上伊达的三个苹果
there must be at least four apples.
篮子里至少有四个苹果
Shit. If Date doubts him now, Ui will get more points.
糟了 如果伊达现在质疑初 他就能得五分
Shunichiro Date, do you wish to call or doubt?
伊达俊一郎 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Doubt.
质疑
Now for the big reveal.
现在开始判定
The number of apples in the basket is…
篮子里的苹果数量是…
one.
一个
Shunichiro Date guessed correctly, and wins five points.
伊达俊一郎质疑正确 获得五分
Ui Saito guessed incorrectly, and loses five points.
齐藤初猜测错误 扣五分
Your tiles are revealed, and you must concede.
你要亮牌 并被淘汰出局
Impossible. There must be some mistake!
不可能 一定是弄错了
This tickles my feathers.
太有意思了
Human betrayal is a sweet thing.
人类的背叛真有看头
There's no mistake.
没有弄错
I don't have a single apple.
我一个苹果也没有
Date.
伊达
What are you doing?
这是怎么回事？
The psychologist Shunichiro Date.
心理学家伊达俊一郎
Many people who connected to Date,
许多和伊达有关系的人
including family and close friends, have committed suicide.
包括他的家人和好朋友 他们都自杀了
What?
为什么？
I don't know the details,
我不清楚详情
but there are rumors that Date drove them to suicide.
但据说是伊达逼他们自杀的
And his purpose for doing so…
他这样做的目的是…
Human observation.
观察人类的反应
Brilliant!
太棒了
That beautiful face of yours, twisting in despair!
你帅气的面庞在绝望中扭曲
All humans before me are simply guinea pigs.
在我眼里 所有人都只不过是小白鼠
They exist merely to be observed.
他们生来就是要给我当观察对象
He's a total psycho.
这家伙就是变态
You betrayed him just for that?
你就是为了这种事背叛他？
Yep.
对
Well, the correct guesser must make a call.
伊达刚才质疑正确 请叫牌
There are five or more…
篮子里有五个或更多…
oranges.
橙子
Yukari Shikibe, do you wish to call or doubt?
式部紫 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Five? He's on the attack.
五个？他发动进攻了
Yukari,
紫
go for 12 pears.
你叫牌说有12个梨
There are 12 or more pears.
篮子里有12个或更多梨
Twelve fruits have been called, so Teruasa Oda must doubt by default.
她叫牌说有12个水果 所以织田照朝自动提出质疑
As for the results,
现在开始判定
the number of pears in the basket is…
篮子里梨的数量是…
three.
三个
Teruasa Oda guessed correctly, and wins four points.
织田照朝质疑正确 得四分
Yukari Shikibe guessed incorrectly, and loses four points.
式部紫猜测错误 扣四分
Your tiles are revealed, and you are out of this set.
你要亮牌 并被淘汰出局
Teruasa, the rest is up to you.
照朝 后面就交给你了
Your team's doing point transfers too now?
你们现在也玩让分了吗？
I have no sympathy for Ui.
我不同情初
But I don't like this guy's style.
但是我不接受他这种玩法
Teruasa, as the correct guesser, it's your call.
织田照朝刚才质疑正确 请叫牌
First, I watch and wait.
首先我要观察战局
There are two or more zucchini.
篮子里有两个或更多西葫芦
Shunichiro Date, do you wish to call or doubt?
伊达俊一郎 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Doubt.
质疑
Now for the results.
现在开始判定
The number of zucchini in the basket is…
篮子里的西葫芦数量是…
two.
两个
Teruasa Oda, who guessed correctly, receives two points.
织田照朝猜测正确 得两分
Shunichiro Date guessed incorrectly. He loses two points.
伊达俊一郎质疑错误 扣两分
You're out of the set.
你出局了
With three players out,
由于已有三位玩家出局
the second set is finished.
因此第二局结束
Why did Date let Teruasa have his points?
伊达为什么会给照朝让分？
You don't even care about winning.
你从一开始就不想和我一决胜负吧？
You're just enjoying watching us squirm.
你只是享受看我们挣扎的样子
You're twisted, just like Yukari said.
紫说得对 你很变态
I'm sorry for the way I played.
很抱歉 是我自作主张了
My life is in your hands. I'm prepared for you to kill me.
我的命在你手上 你就算杀了我 我也毫无怨言
This tournament
这个锦标赛
has reminded me that the only person I can trust is myself.
让我认识到 我只能相信自己
I'm going to win this single-handedly.
从现在开始 我要靠自己战胜他
I will never be beaten.
我绝不会被打败
I'm so intrigued by you.
你这个人果然有意思
Your obsession with beating your friend is second to none.
这种不顾一切打败好友的信念 真的太厉害了
I want to examine you more.
我想继续观察你
Please, let me help you win this time.
这次请让我助你一臂之力 帮你获得胜利
BASKET FRUITS SET 3
（篮子水果 第三局）
Teruasa Oda, you take the first turn in set three.
织田照朝首先叫牌
There are six or more oranges.
篮子里有六个或更多橙子
Straight to six?
一上来就叫六个？
But it's not worth much compared to an apple or pear.
但他没有叫分数高的苹果或梨 而是叫了橙子
That makes it hard to analyze.
这样的叫法确实让人难以判断
Shunichiro, do you wish to call or doubt?
伊达俊一郎 你要叫牌还是质疑？
There are two or more apples.
篮子里有两个或更多苹果
Leave out apples?
不选苹果？
In the next set, we don't put any apples in the basket.
在下一局中 我们不在篮子里放苹果
Then we doubt apples early in the set.
然后提早质疑苹果的数量 拿到五分
How many apples until we decide to doubt?
“提早”到叫多少个苹果的时候？
Ui and Date will probably have two or three, so wait for four.
初和伊达大概会有两到三个 所以等他们叫四个
Once they hit four, we doubt their guess.
等他们叫四个时就质疑
Until then, let's just add one apple each turn.
在此之前 我们每次只加一个苹果
Yukari Shikibe, do you wish to call or doubt?
式部紫 你要叫牌还是质疑？
There are three or more apples.
篮子里有三个或更多苹果
Ui Saito, call or doubt?
齐藤初 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Doubt.
质疑
Already?
这么早就质疑？
Then let's see.
现在开始判定
The number of apples in the basket is…
篮子里的苹果数量是…
zero.
零个
Ui Saito was correct. Five points.
所以齐藤初质疑正确 得五分
Yukari Shikibe, you were wrong. You lose five points.
式部紫猜测错误 扣五分
TERUASA 5 DATE 4
（照朝 5 伊达 4）
YUKARI -14 UI 5
（紫 -14 初 5）
No apples?
零个苹果？
What a coincidence.
真巧啊
You took the same strategy and left out apples.
没想到你们也决定不选苹果
It's true.
果然啊
You really are close friends, huh?
你们真不愧是趣味相投的好朋友
But why?
可是怎么会这样？
Why doubt so early on?
在叫三个的时候质疑也太早了吧？
Teruasa's strategy wasn't the problem.
照朝的战术没问题
You were the one that gave it away.
是你泄露了你们的意图
What?
啊？
You always pause a little before you make your call.
你在叫牌之前都会停顿一下
But this time you spoke without hesitation.
但是这一次 你却毫不迟疑
Just as if you were carrying out a pre-meditated plan.
就好像在执行预定的战术一样
I never let my guard down.
我从未放松警惕
I never take my eyes off you.
也从未停止对你的观察
My acting was that bad.
怪我的演技不够成熟
Yukari Shikibe, you're out.
式部紫 你被淘汰出局
Saito Ui, as the correct guesser, you go next.
齐藤初质疑正确 请叫牌
There is one or more fig.
篮子里有一个或更多无花果
Ui is still working with Date.
初仍然和伊达协作
How should I play it?
我要怎么进攻？
Teruasa Oda, do you wish to call or doubt?
织田照朝 你要叫牌还是质疑？
There are two or more figs.
篮子里有两个或更多无花果
Shunichiro Date, do you wish to call or doubt?
伊达俊一郎 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Surely Date will call pears
伊达肯定会叫梨
so that Ui can take the points next.
然后让初赢得梨的分数
There are 12 or more oranges.
篮子里有12个或更多橙子
Oranges?
橙子？
Twelve fruits have been called, so Ui Saito must doubt by default.
由于他叫了12个水果 齐藤初自动提出质疑
Let's take a look.
现在开始判定
The number of oranges in the basket is…
篮子里的橙子数量是…
seven.
七个
Ui Saito guessed correctly and receives three points.
齐藤初质疑正确 获得三分
Unfortunately, Shunichiro Date was wrong. Three points deducted.
伊达俊一郎猜测错误 扣三分
UI - 8 DATE - 1
（初 8 伊达 1）
Your tiles are revealed. You're out.
现在亮牌 你出局了
DATE
（伊达）
Why?
为什么？
Why would Ui get him to call oranges for three points,
初为什么让他叫橙子来赢三分
rather than pears for four points?
而不是叫梨来赢四分
Don't you get it, Teruasa?
你还没明白吗 照朝？
I'm going to win by taking the highest number of points from you.
我要从你手上赢得最多的分数 从而打败你
Ui Saito, as the correct guesser, it's your turn to call.
齐藤初质疑正确 请叫牌
There are five or more pears.
篮子里有五个或更多梨
Teruasa Oda, do you call or doubt?
织田照朝 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Neither Yukari nor I have a pear.
紫和我都没有梨
There are only two pears in Date's hand.
伊达的牌里只有两个梨
DATE
（伊达）
It all hangs on whether Ui has three pears.
那就看初有没有三个梨了
He's made flawless guesses up until now,
目前为止 他在叫牌时还没失过手
so he must have three pears.
所以他一定有三个梨
Whether I make a new call, or doubt his call, I'll lose.
无论是叫新的牌 还是质疑他 我都会输
So…
所以…
There are five or more figs.
篮子里有五个或更多无花果
Ui Saito, do you wish to call or doubt?
齐藤初 你要叫牌还是质疑？
What are you going to do now?
你会怎么做 初？
There are six or more figs.
篮子里有六个或更多无花果
I've got him.
机会来了
Yukari had two figs, Date had one fig, and I don't have any.
紫有两个无花果 伊达有一个 而我没有
Three in total.
那么一共有三个无花果
Unless Ui has three figs, there can't be six.
如果初没有三个无花果 那么总数不会达到六个
But Ui has three pears,
他有三个梨
so he can't have more than two figs.
所以他的无花果不超过两个
Doubt.
质疑
I'll reveal the results.
现在开始判定
The number of the figs in the basket is…
篮子里的无花果数量是…
six.
六个
As the correct guesser, Ui Saito wins one point.
齐藤初猜测正确 得一分
Teruasa Oda, you were wrong. One point deducted.
织田照朝质疑错误 扣一分
You're out.
你出局了
How…
难道…
In my hand, I had…
在我的牌里
two zucchini,
有两个西葫芦
and…
还有…
three figs.
三个无花果
I'm an idiot.
我太傻了
He called five pears when he doesn't even have one?
他一个梨都没有 却叫了五个梨？
He knew exactly what I would think.
我的想法全被他看穿了
I've nearly won.
我就要赢了 照朝
I'll get that last point, just watch.
我一定会得到最后一分的
Bring it on.
来吧
Ui,
初
I will beat you no matter what.
我一定打败你
OROCHI…
大蛇…
Yes, you're right.
你想得对
Who was that?
刚才那是谁？
I don't know, but someone's definitely following us.
不知道 但一定有人在跟踪我们
It's me. Famous YouTuber Mitsuru Asai.
是我 知名Youtube主播浅井满
-Know who I am? -No, I don't.
-你知道我是谁吧？ -不知道
Yukarin's pretty hot, but you're cute too.
小紫很漂亮 但你也很可爱
Let me post you on my channel.
我把你发到我的频道里吧
-Wait－ No thanks. -How 'bout it?
-不要 不用了 -怎么样？
-Don't be so unfriendly! -Get off.
-别这么冷淡嘛 -放开
I'll pay you if you want. Here, look.
我会付钱的 来 看镜头
Senya?
潜夜？
Geez. I thought I saw you running off somewhere.
我就说看到你乱跑了嘛
Wait… Who are you?
等等 你是谁来着？
I told you, I'm the famous YouTuber Asai!
我说了 我是知名YouTube主播浅井
I'm your next opponent.
我是你下一场比赛的对手
Oh, yeah. You're playing too?
你也参赛？
I'd rather fight Morin alone.
我更想跟小毛利单挑呢
Whatever.
什么？
You think you're gonna get a proper fight?
你以为这会是一场 势均力敌的较量吗？
Dragon King Mori is a monster.
毛利龙王就是个怪物
They say even AI that can predict 500 million moves can't beat him.
据说即使是能预测 五亿步棋的人工智能也没法打败他
500 million?
五亿步？
Yikes!
可怕
Oh, really?
啊？
Now I'm even more excited.
现在我更期待了
I just remembered.
我想起来了
You're Yukari from Super Funky Pixies.
你是“超时髦妖精”里的紫
Yes.
对
It's fascinating to see a current idol competing in the tournament.
当红偶像也来参加这个锦标赛 真是有趣啊
I'd love to chat over a cup of tea sometime.
可以的话 下次一起喝茶吧
Ui,
初
I have a plan that will secure your win.
我有一个可以保你必胜的办法
What is it?
什么办法？
Yukari.
紫
I'm sorry, Teruasa.
抱歉 照朝
I made a mistake.
上一局我失误了
Hey!
喂
Cheer up.
不要泄气
Teruasa.
照朝
It wasn't your fault.
那不是你的错
I played terribly, that's all.
是我太没出息了
Plus,
况且
he's very good.
那家伙确实很强
Ui knows what my devil power is.
初知道我的恶魔之力是什么
But we still don't know either of theirs.
但我们还不知道他们俩的恶魔之力
I wonder when they'll use them.
不知道他们会在什么时候使用
If only you had a secret weapon rather than Ui.
要是你能有 齐藤初所没有的秘密武器就好了
A secret weapon.
秘密武器
BASKET FRUITS SET 4
（篮子水果 第四局）
It's your turn first, Ui Saito.
齐藤初 请叫牌
There is one or more zucchini.
篮子里有一个或更多西葫芦
What is it?
什么办法？
You're Yukari from Super Funky Pixies.
你是“超时髦妖精”里的紫
Now we can listen to their strategy.
我们可以窃听他们的战术
Date, you－
伊达 你…
Don't tell me you think I'm playing dirty.
不要说我的手段卑鄙
If you really want to win against Oda…
如果你真的想赢织田
then you can't be picky about how you do it.
就要不择手段
This time, don't choose any oranges.
这次不要选橙子
As for the others…
至于其他水果…
Teruasa Oda, do you wish to call or doubt?
织田照朝 你要叫牌还是质疑？
There is one or more fig.
篮子里有一个或更多无花果
Teruasa, I know what all of your marbles are.
照朝 你选的牌我都知道了
Shunichiro Date, call or doubt?
伊达俊一郎 你要叫牌还是质疑？
There are two or more zucchini.
篮子里有两个或更多西葫芦
Yukari Shikibe, call or doubt?
式部紫 你要叫牌还是质疑？
There are two or more oranges.
篮子里有两个或更多橙子
Here's our chance.
机会来了
Neither Date nor I have oranges.
我和伊达都没有橙子
There are no oranges in the basket.
因为篮子里没有橙子
Ui Saito, do you wish to call or doubt?
齐藤初 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Doubt.
质疑
Then let's take a look.
现在开始判定
The number of oranges in the basket…
篮子里的橙子数量是…
If I get three points, I'll be on 12.
如果能得到三分 我就有12分
I'm the winner.
那样我就赢了
Six.
六个
Yukari Shikibe wins three points for guessing correctly.
式部紫猜测正确 得三分
Ui Saito loses three points.
齐藤初扣三分
Your tiles are revealed, and you're out.
你要亮牌 并被淘汰出局
What the hell?
怎么回事？
Surely not.
难道…
You've been bugged.
你被窃听了
I THINK IT WAS DATE
（是伊达干的）
This time, don't choose any oranges.
这次不要选橙子
As for the others,
至于其他水果…
first, go for one fig.
首先叫一个无花果
Ui Saito, you're out!
齐藤初 你出局了
Well, since you guessed correctly, it's your turn, Yukari Shikibe.
式部紫猜测正确 请叫牌
There are 12 or more apples.
篮子里有12个或更多苹果
Twelve fruits have been called, so Teruasa Oda must doubt by default.
由于她叫了12个水果 因此织田照朝自动提出质疑
Let's see the results.
现在开始判定
The number of apples in the basket is…
篮子里的苹果数量是…
three.
三个
Teruasa Oda wins five points for guessing correctly.
织田照朝质疑正确 得五分
Yukari Shikibe loses five points for an incorrect guess.
式部紫猜测错误 扣五分
Your tiles are shown and you must fold.
你要亮牌并被淘汰出局
TERUASA 9 - YUKARI -16 UI 6 - DATE 1
（照朝 9 紫 -16 初 6 伊达 1）
If Teruasa can get one more point, and knock Date out of the set, he'll win.
如果照朝再赢一分 然后把伊达淘汰 那他就赢了
From the look on his face,
看初的眼神
Ui hasn't given up yet.
他还没有放弃
Teruasa Oda, as the correct guesser, it is your turn to call.
织田照朝质疑正确 请叫牌
There are four or more zucchini.
篮子里有四个或更多西葫芦
Shunichiro Date, do you wish to call or doubt?
伊达俊一郎 你要叫牌还是质疑？
Date doesn't have any zucchini.
伊达没有西葫芦
Yukari Shikibe didn't have any either.
式部紫也没有
So if Teruasa has more than two, he should call.
如果照朝有超过两个西葫芦 那么伊达该叫牌
But if he has one, or none, he should doubt.
如果他有一个或零个 那么伊达该质疑
Which is it?
该怎么选？
The game hangs on this point.
现在是决定胜负的关键
I've been waiting a long time
我等了这么久
for this moment.
就是为了这一刻
HIJACKED SIGHT
（强制视觉交换）
Unleash Hijacked Sight.
启动强制视觉交换
Is that your devil power?
这是伊达的恶魔之力？
Oda and I will exchange vision for ten seconds.
织田和我将会交换视觉十秒
What? My vision's gone black.
怎么回事？我的眼前一片漆黑
What?
嗯？
I can't see the tiles.
看不到他的牌
Wait.
等等
They won't budge. No.
动不了 难道…
That's right.
对
I fixed them in place using Limited Perfect.
我使用有限完美将它们固定了
LIMITED PERFECT
（有限完美）
Time's up.
时间到了
My own vision is back.
我的视觉恢复了
It worked! You did it.
太好了 照朝做得好
Wrong.
错了
The real game starts now.
真正的比赛才刚开始
Just as planned, I got Teruasa to use his power.
逼照朝使用恶魔之力是我策划的
Unleash
启动
Yes-Man Sheep.
肯定顺从的羊
YES-MAN SHEEP
（肯定顺从的羊）
Teruasa,
照朝
from now on, when I ask you a question,
从现在开始 当我向你提问时
you answer truthfully, with yes or no.
你都得如实地用“是”或“否”来回答
Seriously? A power like that makes you invincible.
怎么能这样？那就太无敌了
Teruasa…
照朝
do you have two or more zucchini?
你有两个或更多西葫芦吗？
Teruasa, don't answer him.
照朝 不要回答
Answer me, Teruasa.
回答我 照朝
Yes.
是
Why are you smiling?
你在笑什么？
You're the one I was watching.
我其实观察的是你
The power Yes-Man Sheep
“肯定顺从的羊”这个能力
forces people to answer with "yes," no matter what I ask.
能强迫别人回答“是” 无论我问的是什么
That's right.
没错
Your expression told me everything.
你的反应说明了一切
Teruasa's real answer was, "no."
照朝的真正答案是“否”
He doesn't have two or more zucchini.
他没有两个或更多西葫芦
So there are no more than three zucchini in the basket.
所以篮子里没有三个或更多西葫芦
Date, you should choose, "doubt."
伊达 你应该选择提出质疑
Exactly.
我知道了
I'm sorry, Teruasa.
对不起 照朝
Doubt.
质疑
Now for the results.
现在开始判定
The number of zucchini in the basket is…
篮子里的西葫芦数量是…
four.
四个
Teruasa Oda wins two points for guessing correctly,
织田照朝猜测正确 得两分
but Date loses two points for an incorrect guess.
伊达质疑错误 扣两分
You're out.
你出局了
This brings the fourth set to a close.
第四局到此结束
With 11 points, the winner of Basket Fruits is…
由于有分数达到了11分 所以“篮子水果”的胜者是…
Teruasa Oda.
织田照朝
What a delightful battle.
这个对决真是有趣啊
Teruasa!
照朝
Thanks for your help.
谢谢帮了我
It makes no sense.
这不可能
Did you see through my lie?
我对我的能力说了谎 这被你看出来了？
I waited until the very end to do my part.
我是等到最后才发挥自己的作用
I never let my guard down.
我从未放松警惕
I never take my eyes off you.
也从未停止对你的观察
You put on an act because I was watching you?
你知道我在观察你 所以你演戏给我看？
When people are watching,
当有人看着时
idols are always performing.
偶像明星永远可以演戏给人看
Plus…
而且…
Yukari,
紫
my secret weapon is you.
我的秘密武器是你
Teruasa's words inspired me.
照朝的话启发了我
I couldn't have won alone.
我一个人绝对赢不了
Yukari and I worked together from start to finish.
紫和我从一开始就并肩作战
But…
但是…
you're the one who taught me that I'm stronger with friends around me.
是你教会了我 朋友能让我更加强大
Teruasa Oda won?
织田照朝赢了？
Yes.
是的
That means that Teruasa Oda
这意味着织田照朝
controls the lives of Yukari Shikibe, Ui Saito, and Shunichiro Date.
掌控着式部紫、 齐藤初和伊达俊一郎的性命
The Guide will be very happy.
引领者大人一定会非常高兴
I knew you'd win, Terurin.
不愧是小照照 你果然赢了
Now you can fight me in the final.
这样你就能跟我一决胜负了
You still have to play the second game.
你还要比第二场呢
I'll win.
我会赢的
Promise.
我保证
Okay.
好
Where's Ui?
初呢？
I don't know. I can't find him.
不知道 我没找到他
You two need to speak properly.
你们俩得好好聊聊
Of course, that's what I wanted.
当然 我也是这么想的
Thank you for helping Teruasa.
谢谢你帮了照朝君
It was nothing. I didn't do it for you.
没什么 我不是为了你帮他的
Hey, Teruasa,
照朝君
I think I might have found Gungnir's hideout.
我可能找到永恒之枪的隐匿地点了
What?
什么？
There was some kind of underground facility.
这里有某种地下设施？
But I didn't have time to look any further because of the game.
但是因为要比赛 我没有时间深入探查
What the hell?
为什么？
GET READY…
（重大预告）
This game is played using clay.
这个比赛要使用黏土
It's way more difficult than I thought to make it look like a dog.
把它弄得像一只狗 比我想象的难多了
You fell straight into the trap I set.
你掉入了我设的圈套
Isn't family more important to you?
家人对你来说不是更重要吗?
Why bother making us compete in the games?
为什么要费心让我们在比赛中竞争？
I have to stop them from getting what they want.
我要阻止他们实现企图
A SHOCKING FINALE
（刺激的大结局）